# **Lucas Michael Lopatka**

## **About**

I provide discerning international clients with intuitive, engaging, reliable and secure software solutions, solving complex business problems for a wide range of industries.

With over 15 years of professional software development experience, you can count on me to help you bring your concept to life - on time, on budget

# **Work Experience**

Apr 2021 - Feb 2024

# **Opn Payments (Omise Thailand)**

Senior Software Engineer, Technical Lead

- Lead various development teams of 3-8 developers.
- Lead Agile planning activities and backlog management.
- Responsible for mentoring junior and associate engineers.
- Technical lead for Opn / Omise's transition to Single Sign-On.
- Architect and lead development of Single-Sign On libs and services.
- Frontend lead for the development of Virtual Credit Card applications.
- Contributor to the development of Omise's Merchant Dashboard v2.
- Creation of various microservice applications in Node.js and Go.
- Responsible for the design + maintenance of various CI/CD pipelines.
- Maintain technical documentation for various applications.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: TypeScript, React, Node.js, Ruby, Go, AWS, Kubernetes

Nov 2019 - Mar 2021

**CGI Inc.** (Government of British Columbia / Service BC), Victoria, BC, Canada *Senior Software Engineer, Team Lead* 

- Developed open source applications for Service BC.
- Lead various development teams of 3-5 developers.
- Responsible for mentoring junior and associate engineers.
- Responsible for Agile planning activities and backlog management.
- Lead development of scheduling application for Sheriffs BC.
- Lead development of Name Request engine for BC Registries.
- Lead development of Electronic Forest Management system.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: TypeScript, React, Node.js, Python, OpenShift, Kubernetes

Feb 2019 - Apr 2019

**BC Developers Exchange / A.O.T Technologies,** Victoria, BC, Canada *Application Delivery Lead* 

- Collaborated with stake-holders / B.A's to design PWA.
- Lead development of UI components and screens.
- Structured development team to deliver using scrum agile.
- Automated load, regression, smoke and integration tests.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: ES7, Vue.js, Node.js, Postgres, OpenShift

#### Feb 2013 - Dec 2014

## Alberta Motor Association Insurance Inc., Edmonton, AB, Canada

Technical Lead (Jun 2013 - Dec 2014)

- Replaced legacy "Front-Tier" ERP for insurance claims.
- Integrated CGI AutoPlus and Kanetix Rating Engines with AgentView.
- Redesigned Web API and WCF domain services.
- Prototyped application screens and workflows.
- Lead design and development of UI components and screens.
- Collaborated with PO / B.A's to design applications and services.
- Tasks: Front-end Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: JS, Kendo UI, C#, Web API, Entity Framework, SQL Server

## .NET Developer (Feb 2013 - May 2013)

- Collaborated with product owner / B.A's to design new applications.
- Designed responsive application screens and workflows.
- Implemented UI components and application screens.
- Designed Web API and WCF domain services.
- Tasks: Web Development, UI Design
- Tech: Razor, C#, Web Forms, Entity Framework, SQL Server

#### 2006 - 2011

## Blue Collar Software Development Ltd.

# Owner / e-Commerce + CMS Developer

- Designed responsive website and e-commerce templates.
- Designed and developed custom extensions for various platforms.
- Won Best Job Board at the Global Recruiter Asia Pacific Awards
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: PHP, JavaScript, Magento, WordPress, OpenCart, MySQL

## **Contract and Freelance Jobs**

#### Jul 2017 - Feb 2019

# Carbeeza Inc. / Interdynamix Ltd.

#### Frontend Applications Lead (Contract)

- Collaborated with stake-holders to design automotive sales platform.
- Prototyped application screens and workflows.
- Lead planning activities for small team of frontend developers.
- Responsible for delivery of consumer portal and dealer applications.
- Responsible for creation and testing of various Node.js microservices.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: ES7, React, Java Spring Boot, Postgres, OpenShift

#### Jul 2015 - July 2017

## Caffe Tech Ltd., Edmonton, AB, Canada

#### **Solutions Developer** (Contract)

- Designed hybrid point-of-sale app using React and Cordova.
- Integrated Star Micronics hardware (Java/iOS) with iOS app.
- Created custom integration linking Magento and QuickBooks.
- Created custom inventory management and invoicing microapps.
- Created payment and shipping/drop-shopping integrations.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: ES6, React, Redux, PHP, Slim, Doctrine, Magento, MySQL

#### Aug 2015 - Aug 2016

# VEST Ltd. / Sportech PLC, Edmonton, AB, Canada

Primary UI Designer and Application Developer (Contract)

- Collaborated with stake-holders to design app.
- Created hybrid app for Android using Angular.js and Cordova.
- Created backend services using Slim, Doctrine and MySQL.
- Created CI/CD pipelines using Docker, AWS, and Azure.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: ES5, Angular, Kendo UI, PHP, Slim, Doctrine, MySQL

#### Feb 2015 - Jul 2015

# Corrpro Canada Inc., Edmonton, AB, Canada

**Lead Full-Stack Developer** (Contract)

- Collaborated with stake-holders to design custom tracking app.
- Created desktop app using WinForms with SSRS reporting.
- Structured development teams to deliver using scrum agile.
- Automated load, regression, smoke and integration tests.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: C#, WinForms, Entity Framework, SQL Server, SSRS

#### Feb 2015 - Jul 2015

# Challenger Fleet Management Ltd., Edmonton, AB, Canada

Lead Full-Stack Developer (Contract)

- Collaborated with stake-holders to design custom ERP system.
- Implemented backend services using Web API and MS SQL.
- Structured development teams to deliver using scrum agile.
- Automated load, regression, smoke and integration tests.
- Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, DevOps
- Tech: Angular.js, C#, Web API, Entity Framework, SQL Server

# Apr 2010 - Jun 2014

# RMG Selection, Beijing City, China

Webmaster (Freelance)

- Designed and developed responsive website template for WordPress.
- Designed and developed custom Job Board extension for WordPress.
- Won Best Job Board at the Global Recruiter Asia Pacific Awards
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, WordPress, MySQL, Apache

#### May 2011 - Oct 2012

#### Carsgone.com, Edmonton, AB, Canada

**Primary Application Developer** (Contract)

- Collaborated with stake-holders to design web applications.
- Architect, design and developed web application and API.
- Implemented multi-threaded solution to parse massive data feeds.
- Optimized search indexing and caching using Sphinx Search Server.
  Tasks: System Architecture, Development, UI Design, Deployment
- Tech: PHP, Kohana / Codelgniter, MySQL, Sphinx OSS, ImageMagick

## Jun 2011 - Aug 2011

## **SpaSation,** Edmonton, AB, Canada

Webmaster (Freelance)

- Designed and developed responsive website template for OpenCart.
- Designed and developed custom shipping extension for Canada Post.

- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, OpenCart, MySQL, Apache

#### Apr 2011 - Jun 2011

## Visma, Oslo, Norway

WordPress Extension Developer (Freelance)

- Developed WordPress plugins to display and manage products.
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, WordPress, MySQL, Apache

#### Dec 2010 - Mar 2011

# Infinity IT Success Ltd., Bangkok, Thailand

Magento Extension Developer (Freelance)

- Developed Magento plugins to display and manage products.
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: Prototype.js, HTML, CSS, PHP, Magento, MySQL, Apache

## Aug 2010 - Oct 2010

# Xtend-Life Natural Products (Intl) Ltd, Bangkok, Thailand

Web Application Developer (Contract)

- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, OpenCart, MySQL, Apache, ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server

## Sep 2009 - Aug 2010

# Smart Traffic Australia, Bangkok, Thailand

Web Application Developer (Freelance)

- Designed and developed e-commerce website templates.
- Designed and developed custom e-commerce extensions.
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, OpenCart, Magento, MySQL, Apache

#### Sep 2008 - Aug 2009

#### Kantana Group Public Company Limited, Bangkok, Thailand

Web Application Developer (Freelance)

- Designed and developed website templates for Joomla.
- Tasks: Website Design, Website Development, Extension Development
- Tech: jQuery, HTML, CSS, PHP, Joomla, MySQL, Apache -

# **Education**

2005 - 2008 Chulalongkorn University, Bangkok, Thailand

B.A. Degree in Economics

2004 - 2005 McGill University, Montreal, Canada

**B.Sc. Biochemistry** 

#### **Skills**

#### **Preferred Technologies**

- TypeScript / JavaScript / ECMA
- React.js / Redux / Flux / Mobx
- Vue.js / Vuex, etc.
- Node / Express / Nest / Koa
- TypeORM / Loopback, etc.
- Webpack / Gulp
- Jest / Cypress
- Cordova / PhoneGap / Ionic

#### Server, Cloud, DevOps

- Kubernetes / Flux / Helm
- OpenShift Container Platform
- AWS Lambda / S3 / EC2
- Docker / Docker Compose
- Azure Pipelines / DevOps

## **Component + UI Libraries**

- Material UI (React / Vue)
- jQuery / jQuery UI, etc.
- Telerik Kendo UI

- GoLang / Protobuf
- .NET Web API / WCF
- .NET MVC / Web Forms
- Entity Framework / NHibernate
- NUnit / AutoFixture, etc.
- Slim / FlightPHP / CodeIgniter
- DoctrineORM / RedBean, etc.
- PHPUnit, etc.
- Buildkite / Jenkins / CircleCl Apache / Nginx / IIS
- VirtualBox / VMWare
- Git / GitHub / GitLab
- Bootstrap 3 + 4
- DevExpress

#### **Databases**

DynamoDB / Postgres / Mongo MS SQL / SQLite / MySQL

#### **UI + Graphic Design**

- Adobe Creative Suite Photoshop / Illustrator, etc.
- Axure / Sketch / InVision, etc.

# **MY EXPERTISE**

# **Concepts and Skills**

- User Interface Design
- Mobile Applications
- Hybrid Apps + PWA's
- Server-Side Rendering
- Static Site Generators

- Micro + n-Tier services
- RESTful Architecture
- Database Development
- Serverless / Edge
- Containerization + Cloud

# **Industry Experience**

- Inventory Management
- Media and Asset Management
- e-Commerce Applications
- Point-of-Sale Integrations
- Accounting Integrations
- Automotive Classifieds

- Automotive Integrations
- FinTech Solutions
- Fuji Electric Vending Machines
- MEI Coin and Bill Acceptors
- Star Micronics Hardware Integrations